# Gary M Davis

437 Tara Lane, Webster, New York 14580 585·301·0467

#### **USER EXPERIENCE DESIGNER**

https://usersimple.com gary.davis@gmail.com

## Summary

I am a collaborative UX Design Lead with a strong background in design thinking, user-focused design, design systems, wireframing, visual design, prototyping, and front-end development. I have a proven track record of transforming complex B2B applications and product experiences to drive measurable improvements in usability, user engagement, and customer satisfaction.

## Experience

XEROX Rochester, NY Senior User Experience Designer

AUG 2024 - Present

- Designed solutions for Al-powered document processing workflows, focusing on human-in-the-loop verification and classification to integrate machine learning capabilities with manual verification seamlessly.
- Collaborated directly with end users to help create intuitive workflow management tools for tracking contracts and assignments through document processing centers, improving operational visibility and processing efficiency.
- Enhanced customer checkout experiences for a corporate print-shop fulfillment e-commerce platform by simplifying complex combinations for pickup, delivery, charge codes, and payment methods, to reduce friction and improve order completion rates.

**INDEPENDENT** 

Principal Consultant

Webster, NY / Remote

JUL 2023 - JUL 2024

 Provided UX consulting services for a cloud-management startup while expanding expertise in AI/ML technologies and design innovation.

**COUPA** 

Principal User Experience Designer

San Mateo, CA / Remote

MAR 2022 - JUN 2023

- Spearheaded the UX design strategy for a supplier business spend management platform,
   which played an instrumental role in enabling \$43 billion in value for diverse suppliers.
- Redesigned the B2B supplier onboarding workflow, increasing profile completion rates by 40%.
   Also incorporated promotions for a verified program to drive additional revenue through an enhanced onboarding product experience.

#### CLOUDCHECKR/NETAPP

Lead User Experience Designer SEP 2019 – MAR 2022

Rochester, NY

- Devised a UX strategy with a phased implementation for CloudCheckr's B2B cloud FinOps
  platform, mentoring a junior designer throughout the process. This strategic initiative yielded
  tangible improvements across customer value, productivity, and loyalty.
- Devised designs to simplify and automate the complex allocation of costs, discounts, and fees across customers and clients. AWS adopted a suspiciously similar design soon after.

#### **EAGLEVIEW**

Senior User Experience Designer

Rochester, NY

JUL 2018 - SEP 2019

Developed a high-impact design to replace a highly complex image review workflow, resulting in more than 50% increases in productivity and revenue. This strategic redesign significantly improved operational efficiency and financial outcomes.

#### **KODAK ALARIS**

User Experience Design Consultant

Rochester, NY

MAR 2015 - OCT 2017

- Reduced customer support costs by more than 15% by simplifying highly complex B2B document processing tasks into understandable workflows.
- Established a design system and behavioral strategy that drove a professional, consistent look and feel across embedded, SaaS, desktop, and mobile UX design.

#### DELL/KACE

Principal User Experience Designer

Mountain View, CA / Remote

MAY 2011 - MAR 2015

- Led the design of the new K3000 mobile device management from initial concept to product launch in about one year, conducting design reviews at key project milestones.
- Led the clean-sheet design of the K1000 Go mobile app with a seamless product experience across web and mobile platforms. Adopted by one-third of customers in less than 6 months.

#### EASTMAN KODAK

Senior User Experience Designer

Rochester, NY

OCT 2007 - DEC 2010

- Led a strategic redesign of the flagship Picture-Maker Kiosk UI, which increased the perception of quality by more than 20%, vastly simplified workflow, and reduced clutter.
- Uncovered safety and usability issues through human-factors assessments. Recommended changes eliminated the risk of injury and reduced key support costs by more than 25%.

### Skills

- Led complex design projects in team leadership roles, mentored and coached junior designers
- Full-stack skills, including user research, concept, workflow, visual, and code
- Expertise using Figma, Axure RP, Photoshop, Illustrator, and many others
- Direct experience coding with HTML, CSS, PHP, Bootstrap, JavaScript, and jQuery
- Experienced with both Lean and Agile methods and tools such as Jira and ADO
- UX design methodologies, including iteration, affinity diagrams, user journeys, task flow diagrams, and personas

## **Additional Experience**

CURRICULUM DESIGN – Rochester Institute of Technology / NTID GRAPHIC DESIGN – Marietta Hospitality, Cleary Graphics, Inc. INDUSTRIAL DESIGN – Smith Corona, Crosman Air Guns, Ranging

### Education

SYRACUSE UNIVERSITY - Bachelor of Industrial Design

### **Portfolio**

https://usersimple.com